droplr.com 2019-06-30

# Privacy Policy – Droplr™

## Your privacy is critically important to us.

  * We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it. (We can’t stand services that ask you for things like your gender or income level for no apparent reason.)
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  * We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of one of our services.
  * In our product, we aim to make it as simple as possible for you to control what’s visible to the public, seen by search engines, kept private, and permanently deleted.

Below is our privacy policy which incorporates these goals:

It is Droplr’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our service.

## Website Visitors

Like most website operators, Droplr collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Droplr’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Droplr’s visitors use its services. From time to time, Droplr may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its services.

Droplr also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. Droplr does not use such information to identify its visitors, however, and does not disclose such information, other than under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information, as described below.

## Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information.

Certain visitors to Droplr’s service choose to interact with Droplr in ways that require Droplr to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Droplr gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. Those who engage in transactions with Droplr are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, Droplr collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Droplr. Droplr does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

## Aggregated Statistics.

Droplr may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its services. For instance, Droplr may monitor the most popular blogs on the WordPress.com site or use spam screened by the Akismet service to help identify spam. Droplr may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Droplr does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

## Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Droplr discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Droplr’s behalf or to provide services available by Droplr, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Droplr’s service, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Droplr will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Droplr discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only when required to do so by law, or when Droplr believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Droplr, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of the Droplr website and have supplied your email address, Droplr may occasionally send you an email, or if you have signed in with OAuth using your Twitter credentials, Droplr may occasionally send you a Direct Message on Twitter’s website, to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Droplr and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email and/or messaging to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Droplr takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

## Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a service stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the service each time the visitor returns. Droplr uses cookies to help Droplr identify and track visitors, their usage of Droplr service, and their service access preferences. Droplr visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Droplr’s services, with the drawback that certain features of Droplr’s services may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

## Privacy Shield

Droplr complies with the EU-U.S. and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union to the United States. Droplr has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement, and Liability. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>

For purposes of enforcing compliance with the Privacy Shield, we are subject to the investigatory and enforcement authority of the US Federal Trade Commission. Under certain conditions, an individual may invoke binding arbitration as a resolution to Privacy Shield disputes.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Droplr commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. EU individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact Droplr at [legal@droplr.com](mailto:legal@droplr.com)

Droplr, Inc. has further committed to cooperate with the panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs) with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning data transferred from the EU.

## Right to be forgotten

Through your account settings, you may access, and, in some cases, edit or delete the following information you've provided to us:

  * name and password
  * email address
  * company name

The information you can view, update, and delete may change as the service changes. If you have any questions about viewing or updating information we have on file about you, please contact us at support@droplr.com. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days. Under California Civil Code Sections 1798.83-1798.84, California residents are entitled to ask us for a notice identifying the categories of Personal Information which we share with our affiliates and/or third parties for marketing purposes, and providing contact information for such affiliates and/or third parties. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to: support@droplr.com.

If you wish to erase your account and all associated Drop data, you can do so under your account settings page. We do not retain your data after you have deleted your account.

## Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Droplr may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Droplr’s sole discretion. Droplr encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. If you have a droplr.com account, you should also check Droplr’s blog for alerts to these changes. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
